SUMMARY

Full stack Developer with experience in designing, coordinating and developing software solutions.

Programming	Java, JavaScript, Dart, Python, Golang, HTML5, CSS3,		
	TypeScript, C++, Solidity		
Framework	Spring, TensorFlow, Flutter, React-Native, NodeJS,		
Scripting	Shell Scripting		
Libraries/Tools	ReactJS, VueJS, AngularJS, Redux, Vuex, Provider, gin, gorm, jQuery, bootstrap, materialUI,		
Databases	SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cloud Fire Store		

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer- Sezzle, Remote, India April 2018 – August 2021

- Implemented effective caching rules with a combination of in-memory, browser and CDN techniques to reduce server load from ~160/sec to ~20/sec.
- Architected and automated the widget integration to reduce manual intervention as much as possible. Integration time dropped from 45 minutes to under 1 minute.
- Developed a Chrome Extension with OAuth for widget integration. Developed REST APIs with GO and use MySQL database. This tool eliminated the need of a developer for widget integration.
- Authored multiple SDKs and tools around Sezzle's widget with React, JS, HTML, CSS which are used on over 20K websites.
- Developed scrappers with Golang, gin, gorm to check merchant website for widget abnormalities.

Software Developer- Doodleblue, Chennai, India March 2017 – April 2018

- Developed and implemented 15+ public developer APIs for User Creation and profile management. These API's have 50K plus calls a day.
- Developed REST APIs for e-commerce website using NodeJS, express and mongo DB.
- Developed frontend for a job portal using ReactJS, used Web Socket for chat integration and Redux for state management.
- Implemented design changes that increased the performance of application through optimizing and tuning DB queries.
- Created CI/CP pipeline for docker build and deployment.

Teacher Assistant – Northeastern University, San Jose, California January 2022 – Present

• Teaching assistant in Machine Learning and Applied Sciences

EDUCATION

• BE – Vellore Institute of Technology | Masters in Information System – Northeastern University | GPA – 4